{
    "id": "d8670ebff79a43e8be0589ec407c5222",
    "title": "Adverbs and Adjectives Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "da2cdd37aad742efb0b03bc9cf21c157",
            "title": "Adverbs and Adjectives Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "The evening was …………………. cold.",
                    "description": "Bitter is an adjective and bitterly is an adverb. We use adverbs to modify verbs and adjectives.",
                    "answers": [
                        "bitter",
                        "bitterly",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I couldn’t help ………………….. at the joke.",
                    "description": "The expression 'couldn’t help + ing' has the same meaning as the expression 'couldn’t help but + infinitive without to'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "but laugh",
                        "laughing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have never seen a more …………………. cricket match.",
                    "description": "A match cannot be excited. An exciting match keeps spectators excited. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "exciting",
                        "excited",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This movie is ……………….. interesting.",
                    "description": "Very and so are possible here. Too has a negative meaning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "too",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am ……………… annoyed to hear this.",
                    "description": "Very and so are not followed by to-infinitives.",
                    "answers": [
                        "very",
                        "so",
                        "too"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He was ………………. tired that he could barely stand.",
                    "description": "Note the pattern: so…that…",
                    "answers": [
                        "so",
                        "too",
                        "very"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You must not waste your ………………. earned money.",
                    "description": "The correct expression is 'hard-earned money'. Hardly is similar to scarcely. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "hard",
                        "hardly",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "No one can write as ……………….. as he does.",
                    "description": "Neat is an adjective and neatly is an adverb. We need an adverb to modify a verb.",
                    "answers": [
                        "neat",
                        "neatly",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I cannot by ……………… means allow you to go.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "any",
                        "no",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The fish tasted …………………",
                    "description": "Taste is a copular verb. After copular verbs we use adjectives, not adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "awful",
                        "awfully",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The problem looked ………………….",
                    "description": "Look is a copular verb. After copular verbs, we use adjectives, not adverbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "difficult",
                        "difficultly",
                        "difficulty"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………. having read a more enjoyable book.",
                    "description": "The use of never for not is incorrect in many cases. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "never remember",
                        "do not remember",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}